Issy, years ago our village was
wiped out during a monster attack.
Lammis and I are among the few people
who managed to survive the destruction.
Both of our parents ended up dying.
Lammis had her blessing then,
but she was too scared to act.
That's why, to this day, she blames herself
for not being able to save everyone.
I had no idea Lamas went
through such an awful ordeal.
She's always so cheerful.
Once spring comes, the hunters
will become more active again.
Next time, I'll protect Lamas.
Hello there!
It's freezing out here.
I really should have
put on an extra scarf.
Yeah, that one looks gaudy.
What are you even talking about?
Red's my lucky color.
Hello, there.
This stuff always hits the spot.
Is that why you buy the
same thing every day?
What about it?
Am I not allowed to have a favorite?
Catch you later, Boxo.
See you tomorrow.
Thank you very much.
My skin is red and white and pink glances.
I'm hot because I don't know.
If you're my skin, I need
you to worry about it.
All of a sudden, let's go!
I need you to worry about it.
Let's go.
When I'm ready, let's go?
For real, I wish you could have been
there to see their faces when it happened.
Whoa, what a coincidence.
It's funny, I was actually just
about to head over to your shop.
Oh, is that so?
I had to pick up some things,
but I'm going there too.
Also, I think your scarf
is a really pretty color.
Yeah, I'm partial to red myself.
Be a gentleman and help
her carry her things.
You're right, if you don't mind.
Thank you so much, you're too nice.
Here I am again.
I even made sure to dress
up in your favorite color.
And yet all I can do is watch
as you walk away. Alright.
What's going on? Boxxo?
Is that some kind of vegetable?
Are you saying you want me to take it?
Hello there!
Where did these eggs come from?
Wait a sec.
What's this?
Soup stock, made from flying fish.
What am I supposed to do with this?
I don't get it.
Do you want me to stew all of
these ingredients together?
Hello there.
Thank you so much.
With this, I'll finally
catch his attention.
She's super cute!
Gorth, Boxxo, love is the best.
Every day seems to sparkle.
Oh, yeah. Get this.
She cooked me dinner again.
It was so unbelievably good.
Huh?
What's this now, Boxxo?
Are you giving me one on
the house to celebrate?
Ah! It's hot!
That's what you get for bragging.
Hey, Boxo, we're back! Hello there!
It's pretty warm today.
Why don't we get
something cold and bubbly?
Oh yeah, we're going to be setting out
tomorrow, okay? Hello there! That's right.
Time sure flies fast.
You'll be traveling with
the Menagerie of Fools.
Uh-huh.
They said something about
checking on the crocodile fiends.
Crocodile fiends, huh?
They're one of the three
big monster factions
that inhabit the Clearflow Lake stratum.
We defeated the frog fiends
and the two-headed snakes.
So all we have to do is make sure
the crocodile fiends don't multiply!
It's just going to be a scouting mission.
It's dangerous to let their
population grow unchecked.
A king frog fiend popped up.
As well as a giant two-headed snake.
I can't help but feel something
strange is going on in this stratum?
Promise me.
You'll run away if things get too dicey.
Sure!
Boxo and I'll make a run for
it if it's too much, right?
Hello there!
Yeah.
No matter what happens,
I'll keep Lamas safe.
Ah, our guest of honor.
Thanks for waiting, everyone.
It's Lamas and Boxo! We meet again.
You're a welcome sight.
Both of you. Mm-hmm.
Thanks for having us.
Hey, Lamas! Boxo! Whoa!
You be careful out there! We will! Right!
Time to head out!
You two can get on if
you'd like. No, thanks.
I'll walk if you don't mind.
It'll be helpful for my training.
All right.
That just means there's more room for me.
Wait, you're coming too, Hulemy? Why not?
It's an ecology survey.
You'll need someone who actually
knows what they're doing.
Plus, Director Bear
practically begged me to go.
Did she keep it a secret
so she could surprise us?
Well, everything should work out fine
with the menagerie of fools here.
This weather's pretty nice.
If I'm being honest,
I'm not the kind of guy who could spend
his whole life cooped up in a town.
I'll waste away if I don't take
a breather outside now and again.
Hello there!
Is anyone else ready for a little break?
I'm starving right now!
Um, thanks for that.
Don't mention it.
Well, I don't want to just
sit here and do nothing.
Maybe I could throw some rocks.
Not a bad idea.
That's a good way of putting
her absurd strength to use.
Lammis, hmm?
Isn't this one of those
bubbly drinks from Boxo?
But the bottle is a lot harder than usual.
Don't you think he's
telling you to throw it?
Oh, you're right.
Wow, that got some serious
distance, didn't it?
Come on!
I can't believe we get to eat all
this yummy stuff out on a campaign.
They're way better than field rations.
We have Boxxo to thank for that.
As long as he's here, or we won't need
to worry about running out of food.
Hooray!
We don't have to catch monsters
and roast them whole anymore!
Yeah, thank goodness!
I'm so happy I could cry!
Alright then, if you'll
excuse me. Be careful.
Do you have some sort of new
function you want to show us, Boxo?
Hello there.
Looks like there's something
new on your side there.
Not to mention this
strange foldable chair.
What's the hole in the middle for?
Oh, this bag fits perfectly
into the hole in the chair.
All that's left is to
figure out this thing.
So we have a tent that's just
big enough for one person
and a chair with a hole that perfectly fits
a bag. Wait a second. Is this a toilet?
A toilet? Ding, ding.
It's a simple toilet
installed on the sides of
vending machines to help
with disaster management.
I get it.
With this setup, nobody can see you.
And once you're done, you can
cleanly dispose of the bag.
What a clever idea.
Am I right, Boxo?
Hello there.
How convenient.
Ain't I a genius?
If I hadn't convinced
Boxo to come with us,
you wouldn't have had
all these conveniences.
Go on, tell me how wonderful I am.
You don't get to steal Boxo's credit,
and frankly, it's disgusting
you'd even consider it.
Ouch.
We're entering monster territory now,
so you guys better stay
on guard for any danger.
Then you should keep watch too, Captain.
No thanks.
Maybe we should poke
him with a spear. Silly.
He deserves it.
Could you come down, Captain?
We'd like to discuss our
plans for how to proceed.
Yeah, yeah, if you insist.
Hey, Aka, Shiro, you
two scout the area. Huh?
All right, we'll get going.
He wants them to handle recon?
By all appearances,
they look to be more like the life of
the party than responsible party members.
Guess that goes to show you shouldn't
judge people by how they look.
Might as well kick our feet
back while we wait for them.
Boxxo, you got any tasty snacks?
I'd like some sweetened tea, please.
Hello there!
We're back, boss!
You miss us?
Good work, you two.
Take a break, then let's hear your report.
Yes, sir.
Let's see.
I think it was about two hours
northeast of here, right, Aka?
That's exactly right, Shiro.
We found a small marsh with nearly
30 of them splashing around.
30 of them, huh?
How big do groups of these
fiends typically get?
They number from 10 to 50 at the most.
I'd say 30 makes it an average group.
How tall would you say they were?
Let me think.
On their hind legs, maybe
about as tall as us?
Yeah, give or take a bit.
That's smaller than usual.
Have they been short on food since they
can no longer attack the frog fiends?
But I thought the
crocodile fiends were the
most vicious of the three
major monster factions.
If the frog fiend population's
been increasing lately,
wouldn't they be happy since it means
they could more easily fill their bellies?
That's because of the king frog
fiend that recently popped up.
In addition to being absurdly powerful in
battle, they're also exceptional leaders.
Small groups and lone wolves
alike tend to gather to them.
No wonder we had to be so
careful in dealing with them.
If it's not a big group, I don't
see why we can't just leave them be.
Captain, need I remind you
that they're carnivorous?
What do you think they'll do to satisfy
their hunger? Right. Humans, huh? Dang. Huh?
Still, though, the purpose of this
mission was to gather information.
We shouldn't go out of
our way to kill them.
But Crocodile Fiend
materials fetch a high price.
Now's our chance while
they're all starving and weak.
The Vice Captain completely
changes whenever money's involved.
Yeah, she's usually so
level-headed about everything.
I didn't know Vice Captain
Filmina was that kind of person.
Wait, just look at her captain.
I bet they're always short on money.
Fine, then we'll go put them down.
We'll launch our attack in
the middle of the night.
Actually, I'd advise against that.
Crocodile fiends are nocturnal.
They're more ferocious at night.
Oh, really?
We are on the same page.
All right, then.
I want everyone to get plenty of rest
tonight, and we'll move out in the morning.
I'm counting on all of you.
Yeah!
Once the fighting starts,
I'll have nothing to do.
Lamas, don't do anything risky.
And you, if things get
bad, protect Lamas for me.
Hello there.
You've got my back? Thank you.
I wish I could do more to
assist you during the fight.
I've been racking my brain
for ways I could help.
What's up, Boxo?
You changed up the way you look again.
What's this?
Whoa, it's cold!
You mean this is ice?
But why would Voxo spit
out these cubes of ice?
I think he's telling us to
use it in the crocodile hunt.
Huh?
Hello there!
I see, but you'd have to be able
to dispense a ton of ice at once.
Hello there!
Hmm, that's good to hear.
Tomorrow's battle is gonna be interesting.
You could even win a reward!
Hulemy, you're not making sense!
Tell me so I understand, too!
Captain!
The crocodile fiends
have finally come ashore!
They were shivering like they were cold!
Excellent.
Seems everything's going
according to plan. And now,
we'll need a way to obstruct our view so
we can get closer without being noticed.
Covering the whole marsh with
fog magic will be too hard.
Well, if that's a no-go,
maybe we could try
spreading them into groups?
What's going on, Boxo?
That's new.
What kind of shape is this?
What's that?
It's too cloudy to be ice.
Are you making a new type
of hardened snow? Too bad.
Captain, I think maybe he's
trying to say don't touch that.
Perhaps it's dangerous to
touch it without protection.
Hello there.
Oh, thanks.
Look at that.
That stuff's creating a bunch of fog.
You're just full of surprises, aren't you?
If we combine this with my magic, we
can obscure the entire area with fog.
That's a really clever idea.
I knew I'd pick the right
magic item for this job.
You're trying to steal
credit again, Captain.
Honestly, stop your moping
and give us our orders.
Just go and pick them off one by
one like we discussed last night.
Your useless Captain's gonna
sit here and help himself
to sweeten tea while you deal
with the crocodile fiends.
Well, uh, I kind of want to go, too.
But Voxo has to stay and keep dumping
that stuff to keep the fog going.
Will you guys be okay without me?
Hello there!
Of course, we'll both be fine.
I'm actually more worried
about you out there. Got it!
See ya!
We'll be back before you know it!
Bye!
Well, everyone in the Menagerie
of Fools is an experienced hunter,
so I highly doubt they'll
do anything too reckless.
This works out.
I wanted to talk to you for a bit.
Hello there!
As I said before, Director Bear
asked me to come along with you guys.
But my mission's different.
He wanted me to try to
figure out why things have
started to go awry in the
Clearflow Lake Stratum.
I'm not sure if you know this or not,
but in each stratum there
exists a being called a lord.
They appear only on rare occasions,
and nobody knows what triggers it.
Years or even decades can
pass between sightings.
It must be the dungeon boss.
Kind of like the ones
you see in a video game.
Anyway,
seems the director thinks these disturbances
might be caused by the Lord's revival.
Hello there!
Did you know there's a rumor that
if you manage to defeat a Lord,
you'll be bestowed with
an incredible treasure?
Well, even if it is true, there's no way
we could take down the Lord of Estratum.
Huh?
What's going on?
No way!
Are you kidding me?
The Lord's actually here?
Damn it.
Looks like there's even stratum split.
What does that mean?
I've never heard that phrase, but I can
tell right away it's something really bad.
Where's Lama?
She's in the back, knocked down.
Kill me!
Drop all of my hands!
But what about Voxo?
I'm not gonna leave him behind.
Poxo!
What are you doing?
Sorry, buddy.
We'll come back for you, I promise!
Get your damn hands off of me!
Poxo!
I look forward to serving you again.
Okay.
Form change!
Raise durability by 100 to 200,
raise toughness by 30 to 50, though it
might not be enough to make a difference.
Points reduced by 1,000.
1,000?
If I get hit with an attack stronger than
the barrier, it uses up a ton of points.
If that thing hit me directly, I
would have been turned into scrap.
But that's all the more reason I can't
let this big guy go after the others.
I'll use the barrier to expel
these fried chicken lunches.
Great.
Seems it likes them.
In that case, eat on up!
I'll feed you until you explode!
Hello there!
I'm alive.
This has to be its stomach.
Whoa, my points are dropping like crazy!
That means I don't have much time.
I better get to work.
I'll create as much chaos as possible.
Barrier ejection time!
Look at those babies fly!
I'll give your stomach a good cleansing.
Oh, I guess that means it's working.
Too bad it'll only give it a stomach ache.
I can't finish it off like that!
Let's try one of those old gas vending
machines you'd sometimes see around old ends.
I've got an idea that might work.
First, I'll fill up the barrier with gas.
Then, when the pressure's built
up, I'll let it escape all at once.
I need to make a fire.
I'll change into a model that has
the ability to warm up frozen food.
Then, restock an item directly
into my internal microwave.
But I've never tried to do
something like that before.
I'm not even sure I can
actually pull it off.
This bending machine is my body.
Now I've had months to get used to it.
I can do this.
No.
I have to do it.
Yes.
I'll do the same thing with
a towel and a newspaper.
And now the forbidden step.
Heating up a metal can in a microwave.
10 damage.
Durability has been
decreased by 10. Finally!
I'll use the barrier to toss
these items out into the gas.
I look forward to your next use.
Owie!
Where'd it go?
Hold on.
These bones kind of look like
they belong to that thing.
Oh!
This coin?
Could it be the incredible
treasure Hulemy was talking about?
I might as well take it then.
Huh?
Oh, crap. Wait a minute.
Is this that stratum split thing?
Oh, this is bad.
Please, someone with the
blessing of might, save me!
I mean, you don't have to have a blessing.
I'll take anyone strong enough to
carry around a vending machine!
As I plunged into the darkness,
an image came to my mind.
A scene of llamas.
Crying
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I look forward to serving you again.